Hey Manim Community!
Today, I want to show you how you
can generate voiceovers directly in your Python code.
AI generated voices have become realistic enough for use in
most content. Using neural text-to-speech frees you from the painstaking
process of recording and manually syncing audio to your video.
As you can see, Manim started playing this voiceover, right as the
code object started to be drawn. Let's see some more examples.
This circle is drawn as I speak.
Let's shift it to the left 2 units.
Now, let's transform it into a square.
I would go on, but you get the idea.
Let's see how the API works!
First, we create a scene using the
Voiceover Scene class from the plugin.
Then, we initialize the voiceover by
setting the appropriate speech synthesizer.
In this example, we use Azure Text-to-speech.
We use the English speaking neural voice called Aria.
We use the style called "newscast casual".
Finally, we give an option to speed up the voiceover playback
fifteen percent, because the default is a bit too slow.
With the configuration out of the way, it is time to animate.
Let's initialize the circle object.
Then, we need to tell the scene to
start narrating, by calling the function "self-dot-voiceover".
By wrapping our animation inside a "with-statement", we
ensure that once it finishes playing, it will
also wait for the voiceover playback to finish.
This is extremely convenient, and let's you chain voiceovers back
to back without having to think how long they are.
We just need to repeat the same pattern
with self-dot-voiceover and with-statements. Here is something cool.
We can retrieve the duration of the generated voiceover programmatically, and then
use it to define for how long an animation should play.
And that's not even the best part! You can switch the AI
generated voice with an actual recording of your voice very easily.
To do that, you record an MP3 of the final text of your video.
Manim-voiceover then splits your audio automatically and replaces
the AI generated voice with your real recording.
Manim-voiceover makes it much easier to
do voiceovers for Manim projects.
Visit the GitHub repo to start using it in your project.